# Alejandro Sánchez



alex.sanzb@gmail.com



+49 176 23551547



linkedin.com/in/alexsanzder



https://www.alexsanz.dev

# **Summary**

10+ years of experience in eCommerce full-stack development and responsive design, including mobile app development and cross-platform solutions (HTML, CSS, JS, GraphQL), as well experience and understanding of UI/UX design principles and process and mobile payments.

Strong communication & collaboration skills with designers and developers teams. Ability working in multicultural and geographically distributed team. Experience in program management and project management. Team collaboration, work under pressure, proactive approach to problem-solving, entrepreneurship, meeting deadlines and improving results. Fast learning ability in emerging technologies.

### Specialties:

- eCommerce OXID eSales, Magento and OpenCart.
- Web Design/Development: HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, ReactJS, GraphQL & MySQL.
- UX/UI Design: Figma, Illustrator, Photoshop.

## **Experience**

## Senior Software Developer Professional Services

OXID eSales AG

Apr 2017 - Present (4 years 3 months +)

- Develop of mobile and web e-commerce solutions on base of the OXID framework, React.js and GraphQL.
- Integration of a modern working environment using the latest technologies and the best collaboration tools.
- Implementation of Agile Methodologies and CI/CD approach taking advantage of all modern software development best practices.
- E-Commerce Slutions Consultant.
- User-centric approach to web design and development ensuring the client satisfaction.
- Implementation of the OXID eSales shop system, bringing a well-integrated, state-of-the-art digital solution.
- Development of custom client modules and integration of various third-party REST and SOAP services.

## Frontend Developer

Naxcon GmbH

Nov 2016 - Apr 2017 (6 months)

- Responsive website development with the React.js framework and the most important front-end languages (HTML, CSS).
- Integration of REST APIs and PHP environments.
- UX/UI design



#### Weetsi Solutions

Mar 2014 - May 2016 (2 years 3 months)

- Requirements analysis, consulting, architecture design and implementation in coordination with the customer and the development team.
- · Conception, implementation and development of mobile solutions for Android and iOS.
- Support and further development of the mobile application's backends.

## **Software Developer & Technical Lead**

CTIN Centro de Tecnología e Innovación

Sep 2012 - Aug 2014 (2 years)

- Technical lead mobile applications development.
- UX/UI design for mobile applications.
- Mobile app development at Mozilla Mexico for Firefox OS.
- Active member Mozilla-Mexico, supporting in national events such as the "Congreso Universitario Telcel" and "Congreso Universitario de Tecnologías" and promoting mobile applications development using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript.
- Digital content editor for Sochi Winter Olympics Games 2014 platform.
- Live sport entertainment website content production (highlights clips and media galleries).

## Mobile Application Developer

## **Grupo PROMASS**

Dec 2011 - Aug 2012 (9 months)

- Internal system architecture design improvement and implementation of REST API.
- Middleware system development to be used as web service for web and mobile developments.
- UX/UI design and development of cross-platform mobile application for sales team for iOS devices (iPad).
- Insurance quote WebApp development for sales team applying geolocation and online quotation using web-services.
- Integration of eCommerce and mobile payments.
- · Online Support (Help Desk).

# Frontend Developer

#### Freelancer

Apr 2009 - Nov 2011 (2 years 8 months)

- Web and mobile design for new online businesses.
- E-commerce advice on marketing solutions with 24/7 online shops, online payments and mobile payments.
- Migration solutions for payments on mobile devices.
- Analysis, development and implementation of web applications.
- Provision of B2B, B2C, C2B, C2C solutions and ERP / CRM integrations.
- Interface design and development for new systems.
- · Advising customers on the introduction of new technologies
- Implementation of content management systems (CMS) and web hosting.

# Graphic Web Designer

Multimpresos

Jul 2008 - Mar 2009 (9 months)

- Web design, graphic design and multimedia design.
- Development and implementation of a billing system.
- Administration and maintenance of systems for desktop, server operating system (Linux), Apache web server, print server (EFI Fyeri).
- · Network installation and installation of IP surveillance cameras.
- Support and maintenance (preventive and corrective) for computer equipment and Xerox print servers.

# (X) Junior Software Developer

Volkswagen de México

Aug 2007 - Jun 2008 (11 months)

- · Analysis, development and implementation of the software solution to improve the management and control of special vehicles (prototypes).
- Management of special vehicles in the area of the Technical Development Full Vehicle.
- Control, inspection and dispatch of the special vehicles.

## **Education**



## Tecnológico de Monterrey

Certificate, Computer Software and Media Applications 2012 - 2013

iPhone & Android.



### 📖 IBERO Puebla

Certificate, Industrial and Product Design 2008 - 2008

# **UPAEP**

Certificate, Industrial Design 2008 - 2008

## Instituto Tecnologico Superior de Ciudad Serdan

Bachelor of Science - BS, Industrial Engineering

2005 - 2007

Application Development of new processes, Lean Manufacturing, Project Management, Quality Systems, Managing Budgets.

# Sprachenkolleg für ausländische Studierende

B2 Certificate, German Language

2015 - 2016

# **Academie Linguistique Internationale - ALI**

B2 Certificate, English Language

2009 - 2009

## **Skills**

PHP • React.js • GraphQL • Mobile Applications • iOS development • Web Design • Project Management • Web Development • Web Applications • B2B eCommerce

## **Honors & Awards**

1st place Start-up Weekend MEGA - Start-up Weekend

Jun 2014

project: "Cryonix Alternate Reality Game Platform."

Top 10 finalist - Wayra México

Jul 2013

project: "Nearbeats la Red Social de la Realidad Aumentada"

Professional Scrum Master I - Scrum.org

Feb 2020

**Professional Certification** 

DevOps Culture - Oliver Hankeln, DevOps Events

Oct 2019

- Definition of DevOps
- Three Ways according to Gene Kim
- · Relationship to Agile
- · What can Dev and Ops learn from each other?
- Error culture
- Continuous Integration, Delivery, Deployment